Ernest Blumenschein papers
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Ernest Blumenschein papers
1873-1964
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Blumenschein, Ernest
2.1 linear feet
The papers of southwest painter and illustrator Ernest Blumenschein measure 2.1 linear feet and date from 1873-1964. The collection documents Blumenschein's artistic career, his relationship with his wife and daughter, his love of the American southwest, and his involvement in the art community of Taos, New Mexico. Found are biographical materials, personal and professional correspondence, scattered personal business records, writings, a large amount of juvenilia artwork, and photographs of artwork.
Provenance
The collection was donated to the Archives of American Art by Helen Greene Blumenschein, Ernest Blumenschein's daughter, in 1971.
Related Material
Found in the Archives of American Art is a small collection of "Ernest Blumenschein letters and transcripts", available on microfilm reel 3281, and consisting of eleven letters between Blumenschein and Thomas Gilcrease, a letter between Helen Blumenschein and Gilcrease, and the transcript of a 1958 radio interview with Blumenschein.
Additionally, the Fray Angélico Chávez History Library in Santa Fe, New Mexico holds papers related to Ernest Blumenschein, Mary Greene Blumenschein, and Helen Greene Blumenschein.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of this collection was digitized in 2009 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website. Materials which have not been scanned include photographs of artwork, negatives, news clippings, and all but a few printed reproductions of artwork.
Restrictions on Access
Use of the original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Ernest Blumenschein was born on May 26th, 1874 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. He moved to Dayton, Ohio at the age of four, the same year his mother died. His father was a professional musician and composer, who chiefly made his living as a conductor of large choruses. During high school he contributed illustrations to "Tomfoolery," a handwritten and hand drawn weekly humor magazine. Besides his artistic talents, Ernest Blumenschein was a skilled violin player, and was awarded a scholarship to the Cincinnati College of Music. In 1892, Blumenschein auditioned for the New York National Conservatory, and was chosen by Anton Dvorak for the role of first violin. With the income from playing violin, Blumenschein attended classes at the Art Students League.
In 1892, Ernest Blumenschein first traveled to Paris to study at the Académie Julian. While in Paris, he met Joseph Henry Sharp who inspired Blumenschein with his stories and sketches of the American southwest, particularly the Taos area. He returned to American in 1896, rented a studio with another Académie Julian student Bert Phillips, and began a successful career as a commercial illustrator working for magazines such as Century, Harper's, Scribner's, and McClure's.
Blumenschein first visited Taos in the fall of 1898 while traveling en route to Mexico on a sketching trip with Phillips. A wheel on the wagon carrying their belongings broke and they took it to the nearest blacksmith in the area, which was in Taos. Upon arriving at Taos, Blumenschein was struck by the "the superb beauty and serenity" of the landscape and was "stirred deeply." The town made a strong impact on both Blumenschein and Phillips, but while Phillips decided to stay, Blumenschein returned to New York for a short while and continued working as an illustrator. The following year Blumenschein decided to concentrate on painting, and re-enrolled at the Académie Julian while supporting himself with his commercial work. In 1903, he met Mary Greene, an American painter living in Paris and they married in 1905, and began sharing a Paris studio. Their daughter and only child, Helen, was born in November of 1909.
While Ernest Blumenschein continued to study in Paris, he also kept working as an illustrator, supporting himself easily. His illustration work was much in demand by American magazines and book publishers. Blumenschein was commissioned to illustrate Jack London's first book, Love of Life, in 1904. He also worked with other famous writers such as Stephen Crane, Willa Cather, and Joseph Conrad.
Upon returning to New York after the birth of their daughter, Ernest and Mary taught at the Pratt Institute. Ernest spent every summer in Taos. In 1919, the family moved permanently to Taos, with Helen returning to New York for school. It was during this time that Blumenschein co-founded the Taos Society of Artists and became part of the Taos art colony. For four decades, Blumenschein created paintings of the landscape, local inhabitants, the Taos Pueblo culture, and city skylines. He won numerous awards for his work and exhibited widely. His work was responsible for changing perceptions about the native culture and peoples of the area - the Navajo and Pueblo Indians. Blumenschein also indulged his love of the outdoors and sports. He avidly camped, played tennis, and was part of the Taos amateur baseball team. His artistic output in the 1950s was hampered by his declining health, and the death of Mary in 1958. Blumenschein died in June of 1960, and his ashes are repositioned at the Taos Pueblo Reservation.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of southwest painter and illustrator Ernest Blumenschein measure 2.1 linear feet and date from 1873-1964. The collection documents Blumenschein's artistic career, his relationship with his wife and daughter, his love of the American southwest, and his involvement in the art community of Taos, New Mexico. Found are biographical materials, personal and professional correspondence, scattered personal business records, writings, a large amount of juvenilia artwork, and photographs of artwork.
Biographical materials include biographical sketches, school notebooks and curriculum vita, family genealogical materials and other family records, certificates, diplomas, and materials commemorating Blumenschein's election to the National Academy of Design. Also found are scattered ephemera items, such as membership cards, tickets, and travel materials.
Correspondence consists primarily of letters between Blumenschein, his wife Mary, and his daughter Helen. These discuss Blumeschein's career, domestic life, financial matters, Helen's schooling, and travel. Blumenschein's activities during World War I are documented by correspondence with the Committee of Public Information, the Salmagundi Club, and with Aide de Camps of army bases. There are a few letters from other artists and writers including William Glackens, Walt Kuhn, Ward Lockwood, Booth Tarkington, and a long letter from Cass Gilbert.
Scattered personal business records consist of a guest list, a list of Blumenschein works in a private collection, a jury duty certificate, and a car payment record.
Writings include personal, critical, and creative writings. There are writings by Blumenschein about the founding of the Taos Society of Artists and the artistic community of Taos and his memoirs about his first trip to Taos. Additional writings include a satirical discussion of modern art, and essays about artists John Gaw Meem, Joseph Henry Sharp, and Walter Ufer, and discussions of select paintings. Blumenschein also wrote of his travels in Paris, Switzerland, and Pittsburgh, as well as about French churches and cemeteries. Creative writings explore the landscape, life and culture of the American southwest.
Artwork consists primarily of fourteen folders of Blumenschein's illustrations for "Tomfoolery," a handwritten and hand drawn magazine that Blumenschein contributed to in high school. His illustrations for "Tomfoolery" include portraits, caricatures, and sequential art. Also found is one folder of small sketches.
Printed materials about Blumenschein include clippings, exhibition announcements, and exhibition catalogs. There are also brochures related to the Taos Art Colony and a 1902 menu for a Salmagundi Club program/dinner Also found here is a 1915 signed menu from a National Academy of Design event signed by Gifford Beal, George Bellows, and Eugene Spiecher among others.
Photographs include two portraits of Blumenschein and a group portrait of National Academy of Design members that includes Blumenschein. There are also photographs of Blumeschein's artwork and installation views of Blumenschein exhibitions.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms.
Subjects:
Meem, John Gaw, 1894-; Sharp, Joseph Henry, 1859-1953; Ufer, Walter, 1876-1936; National Academy of Design (U.S.)
Subjects-Topical:
Painting--New Mexico--Taos; Taos School of Art; Illustrators--New Mexico--Taos; Painters--New Mexico--Taos; World War I, 1914-1918
Types of Materials:
Writings; Works of Art; Photographs
Names:
Blumenschein, Helen G., (Helen Greene); Blumenschein, Mary Greene; Glackens, William J., 1870-1938; Kuhn, Walt, 1877-1949; Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946; Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934; National Academy of Design; Committee on Public Information; Samagundi Club; Taos Society of Artists
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1873-1971 (Boxes 1, OV1; 17 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1891-1970 (Box 1; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1918-1950s (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 4: Writings, 1880s-1959 (Box 1-2; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Artwork, 1888-1925 (Box 2; 0.25 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Materials, 1891-1964 (Box 2, OV1; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1880s-1955 (Box 2, OV1; 0.25 linear feet)
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Materials, 1873-1971, Series 1:; (Box 1, OV 1; 17 folders)
  Included are certificates from art organizations, honorary diplomas from New Mexico institutions, and materials commemorating Blumenschein's election to the National Academy of Design. Family materials include genealogical records and his parents' wedding certificate. Found are many handwritten biographical sketches, and a typed copy of records kept by Blumenschein listing awards, memberships, patrons, dealers, sales, and exhibitions. School notebooks include notes on chemistry and "natural philosophy," creative writing, and many small sketches. Also found are loose notes, a tennis association membership card, and travel ephemera. Of special interest is a questionnaire about Blumenschein's artistic influences.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Artistic Influences, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Sketches, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificates, 1922-1955, (Oversized items housed in OV1) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Vita, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diplomas, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Genealogical Materials, 1927-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership Cards, 1930-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Academy of Design, 1911-1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes, circa 1900s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - School Notebooks, circa 1888-1891, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Tickets, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Travel Materials, circa 1890s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wedding Certificate, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Certificates, 1915, 1926, (scanned with Box 1, F3) (Box OV1)
- Correspondence, 1891-1970, Series 2:; (Box 1; 0.5 linear feet)
  The bulk of correspondence is between Blumenschein, his wife Mary, and his daughter Helen. Mary's correspondence discusses domestic life, Blumenschein's artistic career, the Taos community, relationship issues, travel, and financial matters. Correspondence with Helen is about school, domestic life, travels in Europe, and discussion of art, movies, and books. Blumenschein sometimes refers to Helen by the nickname of "Bill." Helen's letters sometimes contain small sketches.
  Found are letters from magazines, publishers, museums, galleries, and patrons that record the sale, exhibition, and publication of Blumenschein's artwork. Correspondence from sports organizations documents Blumenschein's interest and participation in athletics. World War I era correspondence is with the Committee of Public Information, the Treasury Department, the Salmagundi Club, and the Aide de Camps of military bases in Kansas and New Mexico.
  Of special interest in this series are an 1891 letter from Harper's Young People evaluating Blumenschein's art submission, a letter from General John Pershing in regards to Blumenschein's portrait of Pershing, and a letter from Blumenschein to "a." discussing the conflict between artistic pursuits and Blumenschein's personal life. Also found are a few letters from artists and writers, including William Glackens, Walt Kuhn, Ward Lockwood, Booth Tarkington, and a long letter from Cass Gilbert.
  - A, 1904-1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - B-C, 1913-1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Blumenschein Family, 1902-1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Helen Blumenschein, 1917-1947, (13 folders) (Box 1, Folder 19-31)
  - Mary Blumenschein, 1904-1947, (18 folders) (Box 1, Folder 32-49)
  - Mary Blumenschein, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Committee On Public Information, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - D-H, 1891-1960 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Mabel Dodge, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Cass Gilbert, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - William Glackens, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - I-M, 1904-1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Walt Kuhn, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Ward Lockwood, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Military Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Museum of New Mexico, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - N-R, 1918-1958 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - John Pershing, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - S-U, 1918-1958 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Salmagundi Club, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Booth Tarkington, 1935-1945 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - W-Y, 1918-1948 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Unknown Correspondents, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Personal Business Records, 1918-1950s, Series 3:; (Box 1; 4 folders)
  The series consists of a guest list for an exhibition at the Grand Central Art Galleries, a list of Blumenschein works in a private collection, a certificate verifying Blumenschein's jury duty service, and a car payment record.
  This series has been scanned in its entirety, except for the car payment receipt.
  - Guest List, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Holdings, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Legal Materials, 1918-1948 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Car Payments, 1923, (Not scanned) (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Writings, 1880s-1959, Series 4:; (Boxes 1-2; 0.5 linear feet)
  Found in this series are writings by Blumenschein as well as a few scattered writings by others. Professional writings include Blumenschein's lectures delivered to art organizations, essays on John Gaw Meem and Joseph Henry Sharp, writings on the artistic community of Taos, and written discussions of select paintings. Personal writings are mostly about travel, including memoirs about Blumenschein's first trip to Taos, life in Paris, French churches and cemeteries, Switzerland, and Pittsburgh, Pensylvania.
  Creative writings mostly explore the life and culture of the southwest. The manuscript for "Pablo, a Story Of a New Mexico Harvest" has an elaborately illustrated cover, while "The Channel Boys' Vacation" contains many illustrations. Additional sketches meant to accompany the manuscript "The Road to Milky," are filed in Series 5: Artwork. There is also a satirical piece about a janitor's thoughts on modern art.
  Writings by others include a series of talks on Blumenschein related to a 1948 retrospective exhibition, an essay on Blumenschein by a Spanish scholar, and a memoir on Taos by Bert Phillips.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by title, either given or supplied by the processing archivist. Writings by others follow Blumenschein's writings. This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - ["About the big fish..."], circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Advice For the Tennis Professional, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - "After a Walk In the Hot New Mexico Sun...," 1912 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Arrival Of the Mail, circa 1880s-1900s (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - [Artists and the "Academy"], circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Billy, the Consumptive Who Whistled Second Violin, circa 1880s-1890s (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Bob Brown Of Bed Rock Ark, circa 1880s-1890s (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - The Broken Wagon Wheel, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Brook Story, circa 1880s-1890s (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - [Buck Herbert], circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - The Channel Boys' Vacation, circa 1888-1891 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - ["Cities..."], circa 1890s-1910s (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - ["English girl..."], circa 1890s-1910s (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - An Evening In Switzerland, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - ["An Excuse For Art..."], 1931 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - [Fragments On Art and Artists], circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - [Fragments Of Creative Writings], circa 1900s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - [Fragments Of Personal Writings], circa 1900s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Funeral and Wedding At Notre Dame des Champs, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - ["Good Opening For a Story..."], circa 1890s-1910s (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Guide to Antwerp Cathedral, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Henry Theobald, Jr., circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - The Hop Fiend, circa 1890s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - "How the Band Won the $100...," circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - In Regard to a Room For Moderns at the N[ational].A[cademy of].D[esign]., circa 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - The Janitor Gives His Views On the Present Art Revolution, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Jimmy Hummingbird, Indian Boy, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - John Gaw Meem, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Joseph Henry Sharp, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - The Kind-Hearted Joy, circa 1910s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - [Lecture at New Mexico Normal School, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - [Lecture For Pen and Brush Club], 1934, April 21 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - [Lecture to National Arts Club], 1928 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - [Lecture to Taos Lions Club], 1940 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - A Legend Of Taos Pueblo, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - ["Mamby"], circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Modern Art and the Academy, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - My Western Friend, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - [Notes For Talk On Early Days Of Taos Society Of Artists], circa 1920s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Offering to Nature, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - [On Dynamic Synchronism], circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - [On French Cathedrals and Cemeteries], circa 1890s-1900s (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - [On Modernism], 1952 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - [On Nature], circa 1947 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - [On Paris], circa 1890s-1900s (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - [On Pittsburgh], 1934 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - [On Taos Community], circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - [On Visiting a French Church], circa 1890s (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - [On Work Habits (Fragment)], circa 1934 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - One Day Of a Pueblo's Life, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Pablo, a Story Of a New Mexican Harvest, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Paraquet and Love, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Preface For Pioneer Artists of Taos, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Preparatory Dance, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Rhythms Of Nature, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - The Road to Milky's, circa 1890s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - The Ruche, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Schools and the Man, circa 1880s-1890s (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - The Silver Gray Fox, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - ["Smokin' Her Up"], circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - South American Millionaire, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Story Of a Pebble, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Story Of Four Paintings, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Story Of Three Sioux Scouts, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Story Of "Mustache Rouge," circa 1910s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Story Of Paintings Entitled "Moon, Morning Star, and Evening Star" and "Enchanted Forest," circa 1930s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Taos Society of Artists: 50th Anniversary, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "This Is a Hunting Story...," circa 1900s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - To Taos With a Wagon Wheel, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Walter Ufer, circa 1936 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Whoopin' Her Up": a Story Of a "Forth" in New Mexico, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Yellowstone Park, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Writings by Others (Box 2)
    - [Ernest Blumenschein] by Ken Adams, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - [Don Carlos' Circus] by Helen Blumenschein [?], circa 1910s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Art Of Ernest L. Blumenschein by Howard Cook, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - [Ralph Waldo Emerson (?)], circa 1900s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - A Recipe For Cooking Husbands by Amelia Gassette, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - En Homenaje al Pintor Blumenschein by Enrique Lafuente, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - [Shaw Dinner Homage to Blumenschein], 1932 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - [Acrostic Poem] by [?] N., 1927 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [Opening Remarks For Blumenschein Event], 1948 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Broken Wagon Wheel by Bert Phillips, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [Edgar Allan Poe], circa 1910s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - [Ernest Blumenschein] by Theodore Van Soelen, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - [Various Articles On 1948 Blumenschein Retrospective], 1948 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Artwork, 1888-1925, Series 5:; (Boxes 2; 0.25 linear feet)
  This series consists primarily of printed issues of "Tomfoolery," a handwritten and hand drawn magazine created by Blumenschein and others during high school. Issues contain portraits, caricatures, sequential art, and lettering by Blumenschein signed "B" or "Shine." Writings by Blumenschein can also be found.
  Also found are several small sketches by Blumenschein, and sketches for illustrating Blumenschein's manuscript "The Road to Milky's" (see Series 4: Writings). Artwork by others includes a work of juvenilia by Helen Blumenschein, and a small landscape sketch by Mary Worral-Wisca.
  - Sketches, circa 1890s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Tomfoolery, 1888, September-December (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Tomfoolery, circa 1888 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Tomfoolery, 1889, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 27-33)
  - Tomfoolery, circa 1889 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Tomfoolery, 1890, January-March, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 35-37)
  - Tomfoolery, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Artwork by Others (Box 2)
    - Helen Blumenschein, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Mary Worral-Wisca, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Printed Materials, 1891-1964, Series 6:; (Box 2, OV1; 0.5 linear feet)
  Printed materials include clippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, printed illustrations of Blumenschein's work, and ephemera mostly related to the Taos Art Colony. Topics covered are Blumenschein's exhibitions, published illustrations, early years in France, critical reception to his work, Taos Artists Society, the National Academy of Design, and sports. There is a small pamphlet for the Taos Heptagon, an "affiliation of painters" including Blumenschein, Dorothy Brett, and Ward Lockwood.
  Also found are invitations, a program for a "vaudeville" performance at the Salmagundi Club, and two postcard reproductions of Blumenschein paintings that have annotations by Blumenschein on the verso. Of special interest are a 1915 menu from a National Academy of Design event signed by Gifford Beal, George Bellows, and Eugene Speicher among others, and a 1902 menu from a Salmagundi Club event honoring Bruce Crane with many signatures.